e
[Music]
he
a
[Applause]
[Music]
the country fam is in big trouble big
big big
trouble big
[Music]
trouble wow what a day what a day it is
Friday it is Friday so thankfully that's
that's happening um you know y'all this
is this been it's been a crazy a crazy
day um we're obviously going to talk
about what happened between Donald Trump
and zalinski um but before we get to
that we're going to start off with an
update on what's happened in
all these things Quake pan Quake um and
how that's developed right because you
know this is the age of the technocratic
surveillance State like we're we're
getting
increasingly more fascistic and by the
way y'all uh Donald Trump is not going
to remove the Russian sanctions he's not
going to remove the sanctions against
Russia he's extended them for another
year therefore we're still in the age
where YouTube is suppressing content
where they're taking things down and
more than ever the people are asking for
a platform that doesn't use the
algorithms that Elon Musk for example
uses these algorithms that he has uh
pretty much maneuvered to only allow a
certain segment of people that he likes
and that say the things he wants to get
seen on X and we've all seen this same
with YouTube you know that was owned by
Google and essentially decided to just
crash down on anybody questioning Russia
Ukraine anybody questioning you know
talk asking questions about elections
asking questions about covid we've all
been there we've all seen these things
so everybody's been asking wouldn't it
be great if we could just
have some sort of software some sort of
social media platform that could
potentially help free the internet make
the internet free and also stop data
mining us because that's part of the
fourth Industrial Revolution right
that's part of where we're headed this
data mining of sorts where it's no
longer just a war on Military targets
and and countries but also a war that's
psychological and it's always been this
way but I think with the internet and
with big Tech we're now entering an age
where it's all about that data it's all
about how
to navigate these Waters to try to build
a narrative and I think we're seeing it
right now we're seeing that theatric and
that narrative be built especially with
this Trump Administration so um I want
to start off by bringing in our guests
famam did you have any comments before I
bring in our guests no no let's let's
rock and roll I just got a lot of
questions so uh I'll be ready to ask
right so um you know our Our Guest is a
former CIA analyst he's also the uh an
author he's also done multiple shows on
RT including the whistleblowers and has
his own podcast now um and that's John
kyaku go ahead Jamie bring on John kyaku
uh welcome John thanks for coming on
thanks so much for the invitation it's
good to see you good to see you too and
you know um you you are a uh brand
ambassador a panqui right and I am um
you have been around and seen the
developments too and I've just started
working with them and I I have you know
I have seen also just what it is and
what what it has what these people who
have been working so hard have
accomplished and it's there's been a lot
of negativity a lot of uh I would say so
many questions that have surrounded pan
Quake recently John they released a
stack article where uh it was titled
where the heck is pan quake and who is
bad Banky and there in this long article
it explained that pan Quake is now on a
test net and is already worth millions
despite Relentless establishment attacks
and this international team is
essentially taking on now a major Bank
in a fight for a soul and
this this this all started with a small
group of very uh capable developers
coming from an activist background from
Occupy Wall Street people who have their
roots in an anti-establishment movements
right and now this has developed into
what panqui is can you just start off by
telling the audience that maybe is not
familiar you know where is pank Wake now
and what is bad Bank
well good questions both I I want to say
first that i' I'm very proud to have
been associated with panqui from almost
the very beginning uh I meet a lot of
people I know a lot of people uh these
people at pan Quake have devoted their
lives to transparency to equality and to
um to making sure that everybody has a
plat form that they can trust that's not
going to sell their data rat them out to
some intelligence service I've never
seen anything like it and the idea was a
great one from the outset uh with that
said it was such a great idea that it
seems to have come to the very quick
attention of big business foreign
governments big Banks and um and the
problems started really in September of
2022 so the the the company talk
Liberation which sort of is the overall
entity um it was banking in rikic
Iceland we're we're not going to name
the bank there's no reason to we call it
bad
Banky one day without any kind of
warning bad Banky just froze pan Quakes
accounts now the account was was seed
funding uh it was it was the lifeline
the company's lifeline and and they did
this claiming at the same time that they
suspected there was money laundering
ongoing maybe even uh terrorist
financing all of that was nonsense of
course now my own personal opinion and
I'm not an I'm not an investigator I'm
not an attorney but my own uh opinion is
that this had to come at the behest of a
government Banks don't just freeze
uh uh assets for for no reason unless
they're usually so this this went on for
a couple of years uh talk Liberation
which was developing pan quake and pan
Quakes Associated Services had no choice
but to redirect its uh its resources to
addressing this this banking situation
so where the Strategic plans would have
been executed by now this thing would
have been up and running by now it was
set back back because it had to take on
these these Banks now the company went
about it in a very very smart way they
hired proven attorneys attorneys that
had had success uh in Iceland uh
previously and um and they pursued legal
remedies and so that's where we find
ourselves now the the company as you
said correctly is valued in the millions
of dollars they have dozens of employees
now and I mean like
listen I I'm I'm 60 years old but I'm
not a lite I'm not an idiot I I'm pretty
techsavvy I don't know what these people
are talking about half the time they are
so Advanced this technology is so
Advanced that it's it's something that I
think the world needs and so we're
getting there again it's taken a little
more time than we had wanted or expected
because of this this intervention which
we believe is uh is illegal and illc
conceived but we're back on the right
path and it's it's through the
courts yeah yeah and I I want to
highlight right that uh this is a story
of of David and Goliath this is a story
that I think a lot of people who can
follow not just your work but all of our
works in Independent Media and and
people who have been on the side of the
the outliers the anti-establishment The
Hooligans the people who who just have a
different point of view right at the
very very core of it and who say look
we're not going to take this abuse we're
not going to allow these big
institutions from whether it's Banks
whether it's it's government entities
whether it's somebody or something
powerful that has just exerted this type
of abusive Outreach overreach of power
and that story I think affects
not just obviously uh a group of of
software developers that turned you know
talk Liberation um panqui into talk
Liberation which now has several
products that I'm going to ask you about
but also everybody that pretty much has
anything that they're fighting for
perhaps and that spirit is what we've
seen also be reflected in in right now
in in the latest uh news that's been
happening all around the world world you
know we're living in the age of genocide
we're living in the age of mass
surveillance and we need more than ever
to get the information across so you
know it's necessary really 100% agree
you know and one of the things one of
the many things that that I liked about
panqui from the very beginning was that
it's open source code no secrets no back
doors no um uh advertising they don't
take money from governments from
billionaires you know it's everything is
is for the little guy you you said just
a few minutes ago a few seconds ago uh
that this is a David and Goliath fight
that is exactly what it is it's a David
and Goliath fight and one of the things
too that kind of surprised me was that
this Bank unfroze the assets unfroze the
accounts which then just proves that
panqui had done done nothing wrong in
the first place so you know it's time to
pay the piper and I think that as this
thing continues to to wind its way
through the the courts in Iceland the
truth is going to finally come out
everybody's going to be back on track
and uh this product is going to become
available to
everybody yeah so John I'm sorry go
ahead no no no go ahead go ahead well I
want to stay right here okay so John
um this is a David verse Goliath story
and you said so many things there that
really resonated uh with what's going on
uh you said open source right yeah uh I
think that's so important because right
now we've lost the the discussion
remember there was this big discussion
when Joe Biden was on office and a lot
of you know the Twitter files came out
Elon bought it and that's right I don't
want to bag on Matt sayi he's not here
to defend himself but I was really upset
that we were going about saying that
screenshots were okay and not Source
material and also to me it seemed like
to be a plan in which they were saying
conservative voices were being censored
all of us here are pretty much
considered leftists I don't know if you
consider yourself a leftist but I doong
to me John kako and Ray McGovern are the
leftist ex Feds that you know really
kind of align with us they're very you
know Anti-Imperialist me mentality what
not how do we get past uh the Goliath
situation because here they are they
froze their Banks they own the
satellites they own everything there how
is pancake pancake pan Quake yeah going
to be able to push back more of these
hurdles that come up because right now I
know you would probably agree with me
that Twitter is not operating on an open
source system and in fact they only
lifting up their conservative populist
right prot Trump Pro Zionist voices out
there while all of us again are taking a
back seat how do we get through all this
Susie Dawson is the uh is the CEO of the
company I've known Susie for years I
don't think I have ever known someone as
dogged as Susie whether it was defending
Julian Assange even before he was
dragged out of the Ecuadorian Embassy in
London uh or whether it was pan uh pan
Quake or or anything else that Susie's
been involved in when she sets her mind
to doing something she's going to do it
and it gets done so you're right we
don't own satellites uh I don't know of
any friendly billionaires who have their
own you know rocket ships to take up our
own dedicated satellite this is going to
be something we're GNA have to fight
forever I suspect but one of the things
that I've I've seen with my own eyes
Visa v suie um is the fact that she
takes it one day at a time and one step
at a time and every time an issue pops
up that needs to be dealt with she deals
with with it and that's why the company
was not killed when bad Banky froze the
accounts the company actually grew while
the company's accounts were frozen that
says a lot and I have to just as an
aside I have to tell you something else
when sus first first approached me five
years ago now to to five years ago this
month actually to uh offer me this brand
ambassador position one of the things
that she said about panqui has stuck in
my mind and it is that that the servers
are powered using um like geyser power
you know steam steam generated power
from Icelandic geysers so not only is it
open source open code and no back doors
and no no uh capitalist you know
intervention it's green on top of it all
I'm still amazed by that like who even
would think to do something like that I
think it's absolutely fantastic
so to answer your question the only
thing we can do is just keep fighting
that's it and and really this is
something that all of us that are
involved with the company have done in
different ways whether it was in support
of Julian Assange or Julian Assange and
Wikileaks or you know cuttingedge Tech
or human rights or or Palestinian uh
civil liberties whatever we're kind of
used to fighting that good fight and
this is another one of those examples
where you know I think for many of us
I'd be bored with life if I didn't have
fights like this to wake up for every
day that's true that that's a good point
um I want to bring back uh the
conversation as to you know because
there's again there's been you know
criticism as to it's taking a long time
right and I I listen to people's
criticism because I understand like
people are are hungry for something to
fight yes something like Twitter
Facebook you know meta all all of these
you know powerful um institutions that
basically data mining us that they're
basically following us spying on us I'm
glad you brought that up yes so yeah
what I'm sorry yeah well I just was
going to ask you like what what products
have been released because I know panqui
me has been released uh influencers are
using it to substitute yes the links
from like mainstream media say like for
example you post the New York Times
article but then you put it in this uh
panqui thing and then it switches it to
URL and exactly right yes so panques pnq
K.M you've got to check this out um
almost a year ago a group of um of
panques went to a a major International
Conference it was in uh Hong Kong last
year and that was the first time where I
was able to sit with my colleagues
because we're spread out all over the
world literally all around the world we
we have meetings where people have to
get up in the middle of the night to
participate in these meetings because
we're across all of the globe's time
zones we all got together in Hong Kong
and my tech colleagues uh showed me what
panqui domme
was it was so simple and so incredible
at the same time for example just to
come back to your original Point let's
say I want to read an article so I go to
you know bbc.com or whatever it is and I
click on the article and I read the
article well as soon as I click on it
it's collecting all kinds of data on me
all kinds of data and not just because I
read the one article it will continue to
follow me by depositing cookies on my on
my uh computer and and the company well
BBC in that case will sell my data to
another company which in turn will sell
it to um to advertisers and and really
anybody who wants to pay the money for
it including the FBI the CIA and the NSA
which I also object to with panqui
domme it will give you a shortened URL
where they can't follow you anywhere you
can read that article there are no
cookies there is no collection of data
there is no sale of your personal
information your privacy is protected
like I say very simple but very
sophisticated and very safe I mean the
the goal I would I would hope uh at the
end of the day is that everybody would
want to use something like this because
at the very least it it will protect you
as you surf the web now the reason why I
think this was so this is so important
is that here in the United States at
least we're we're having a big problem
it's it's an ethical problem it's also a
legal problem and it's probably going to
end up at the Supreme Court and that is
that the
FBI and NSA
specifically um rather than to ask ask
for a warrant to collect information on
American citizens or what's called us
persons any anybody in the United States
as a citizen or with a green card
instead of getting a warrant to collect
information they just go to x and meta
and all these other uh platforms and
they just buy the data that's it so they
can build a case against you you don't
have any idea that they're doing it you
haven't done anything wrong and more
importantly no judge has any idea that
they're doing this now people have said
to me I hate when people say this but
they say it all the time well if I if I
haven't done anything wrong I don't have
anything to
hide right well that's just as a just as
a a point of trivia do you know who the
first person was that asked that
question in a public venue it was Joseph
Geral he was Adolf Hitler's minister of
propaganda if you have nothing to hide
then why are you worried about what the
government is collecting on you well I
worry a lot because it's none of the
government's damn business what I do on
the internet and so pan Quake will allow
you to do everything that you normally
do going from website to website to
website and you're not leaving a digital
Trail and you do that by using panqui
domme I I think that you know obviously
I'm so excited because I want a fair
playing Ground right as some who's been
censored for quite some time you know we
first got censored it was funny we
started showing uh estein stuff about
six years ago five and a half six years
ago and we were like the first Bernie
Sanders progressives to kind of bring
this into the leftist movement and we
got major traffic there I think
everybody thought it was so unique to
see pasta and fiorella who are Bernie
Sanders supporters talking about Jeffrey
Epstein and connecting the dots well
they spanked us pretty quickly then we
got into elections we kind of have our
same relationship of sorts yours is a
little bit more intense with Rudy
Giuliani but Rudy Giuliani took the
election Integrity movement and then
kind of he told 80% truths and then 20%
lies which really hurt us up but it let
us down a corridor of being censored
even more and to this day you know
obviously our opinions on covid were a
little bit different than a lot of
leftists um and they didn't allow that
to happen so they really hurt us a lot
think a lot of us are eager to get to
that kind of Open Source free platform
but can you get a little bit more into
also this over here because I think this
is important right here Jamie if you can
put that up again can you just show us
how this works a little bit uh John
really quickly like what would we
necessarily put in there and how would
that exactly because we can start using
this today correctly correct yeah yeah
you could that's right you can use this
today uh it it really is quite liter as
simple as a cut and paste so you just
you type in uh what you want to uh go to
where it says paste your link here uh or
you just cut it from another site and
paste it there hit all right uh panqui
link it will generate a link that you
can then paste into your browser and you
can surf
WorryFree it says clean where it says
clean cleans your link prevents big Tech
tracking users that's exactly what it
does archives the content so you don't
have to to worry about going back and
having to repeat all those all those
steps again yeah if you put in like a
New York Times article or
something no I was just saying New Times
article or something yeah Jamie go ahead
and throw something in there but John
this isn't very important because what
you're saying as an ex intelligence
agent right that they're going to also
look at what you're looking at in other
words the way they descri the way they
find the real journalist not the
propagandist is to censor and look at
what you're looking at and this is going
to prevent them from doing this yeah
it's going to prevent them from doing it
and this is something that that for me
is very important what happens if you go
to a a website big Tech is tracking you
and then you go to let's say Google and
you're looking
for let's say abortion clinics nearby or
psychiatrists or uh you know your your
looking for information on your ex-wife
or whatever law enforcement can actually
build a profile against you it may be
correct it may be incorrect but it can
be used to against you and so this is a
way to keep big Tech big government CIA
NSA FBI off your back
damn wow good stuff yeah so well one of
the the other things I want to bring up
pasta and I think you're going to love
this one because this goes along right
along with everything if you go down the
substack article Jamie I'll just copy
paste this for you it's wld Dragnet
domcom okay and oh this is so cool this
is cool and it's scary because I found
my myself there as well of course you
did but um you know uh by the way panqui
is not just uh blockchain it's um it's
not just open source it's blockchain as
well which is important and it's also a
uh blockchainbased social media Network
that for the techie people who might
know it's a layer one blockchain so it's
it's very very secure these are the
things that P and I have talked about
when it comes to elections if you have a
blockchain open- source system how
beneficial that would be but if Jamie if
you go on wld drag
net.com you can find that um this is
this is what's called the the Foss
project or a fast product and this is a
Search tool that essentially
documents that uh what what shows that a
variety of us defense contractors who
had been looking into you all whether
whoever you are social media users right
and basically drag netting them or
targeting them based on their political
affiliation so you can put your Twitter
handle there and it'll give you a list
of all the places where you were
mentioned can you talk a little bit more
about that
John I checked this out when it was
still in beta this is a couple of years
ago maybe three years ago by now and I
was shocked
that one defense contractor in
particular and it's not my job to
protect them so I'll just say it it was
North Rook Grumman
Corporation um had searched my name
hundreds of times it was clear they were
building something uh but I would never
have had any idea that I was of Interest
specifically at North rook brummond and
it wasn't just North Rook brummond
although they were the biggest it was
companies that do business with North or
Grumman and even some of the competitors
for example um I wrote an article in
which I
criticized like McDonald Douglas I think
it was McDonald Douglas this is four or
five years ago now and then there was
this flurry of activity at McDonald
Douglas who is this guy what's he doing
and so
uh you know I was able I was I was
actually in litigation against uh I
actually went into litigation against um
North with Grumman on a on a separate
issue and my attorneys were able to use
this
information uh as as part of our our
lawsuit wow that's crazy yeah it was
pretty cool it would have never occurred
to me that that there even is such a
tool but there it is and it's
free I'm trying to see how that what
would you just go in there and put your
Twitter handle in and yeah yeah yeah uh
well this came about a few years ago so
it might have been if you've changed
your Twitter handle you may not find it
but if you've not changed it you can
find anything um and and you can put it
on there did you show it
Jamie okay yeah so you can go ahead and
um anybody can just go ahead and put in
uh their Twitter handle again and you
just you can just search yourself and
again this is just another uh product
that's been released and it's it's for
everybody right it's for everybody to to
Really benefit from it's not you know
when you when you think of businesses
and when you think of like social media
platforms you think that it's people
that are against you right yeah um that
it's people that aren't on our side so
it's kind of in my opinion revolutionary
to see something like this even attempt
to come out because a lot of us John and
I'll speak for myself too have had a
very negative point of view when it
comes to technology when it comes to any
software because we've seen what it what
it does at the behest of Empire
essentially and well just this week I'm
sorry to interrupt you just real quickly
uh the British government uh is
practically at war with apple right now
because it's demanding a back door into
um Apple's operating system and apple
said that they are willing to shut down
in the UK rather than to give British
intelligence a back door sorry to
interrupt no that's and but and that's
even Apple that that still has you know
they're not as bad as others but they
still have that's right A lot of the
same type of cookies the same type of of
surveillance and and that's crazy that
that it's not even enough for right they
want complete access to everything that
everybody has I say this all the time it
is against the law for NSA to collect
information on an American citizen it is
a violation of nsa's Charter to collect
information on an American citizen so
why then did NSA build a a new facility
in the Utah Wilderness that has so much
computer memory available that it can
hold every cell phone call every text
message and every email sent by by every
American for the next 500 years I don't
want them collecting that information
from me it's none of their
business yeah but I mean the the thing
is we've grown so accustom to them just
being to fully able able to do that yes
and so I I think it's it's crazy and I
think it's also scary for a lot of
people because they still think like
that's not possible that there's no way
that we can have a social media or any
sort of tech platform that's going to
not give information to the powers that
be that's not going to use this
information for advertisement for data
for XYZ so um you know for me it's crazy
that this is happening and there's
another product that pan Quake uh talk
Liberation excuse me has now also um is
also releasing uh they have their uh
it's coming around much very soon and uh
Susie Dawson mentioned it in her
substack and it's called linkme and it's
pronounced link me yeah what is that can
you just explain that because that one
was harder for me to W wrap my head
around yeah link me's link me is just
about the same as
panqui um it it's it's about the same
end product end process where where your
data is being protected it it's part of
a suite of offerings that pan Quake has
come up
with I and go ahead go no no no I mine's
a different yeah go ahead okay no I and
this one I I know is going to be used
mainly by like businesses and by uh
people for example if you're uh any
business person or if you're working on
a project say marketing project and
you're going to uh or you're a say a
journalist right and you have all your
platforms there you you're going to be
able to have all your platforms um and
and be able to look at them so I think
as more information comes out about all
all these you people have to understand
these are separate products under one
umbrella so it's it's not like it's just
one thing it's like several different
things and it that takes a lot of work
and I know nothing about it like for
example software development or computer
programming or or any of that stuff
which is ironic because in my family
there's like you know 10 computer
programmers but I just never got into
that but just understanding the level of
work it takes is um is crazy go ahead
it's it's crazy I'm sorry go ahead no no
no no go ahead finish it no I I was just
going to agree I'm I'm every time we
have a staff meeting a staff Call I'm
amazed at how brilliant these people are
it it's they're able to they're able to
develop products that I I couldn't even
comprehend and then they're able to
explain them in a very simple way where
I could say or I do say gez I I could
use that I I I could get good use out of
that and then they'll send me the beta
and I able to try it and it's as easy as
they said it was it's dramatic to
me so you have all these other separate
products right here under that one
umbrella but the main product panqui
itself is going to be like a Twitter of
sorts or a Facebook or whatever another
operating system where we can go to
where number one it's going to level the
playing field uh open source we're gonna
understand exactly how some voices get
lifted why others get censored which I
think is the big thing because it's kind
of like elections right you can censor
somebody's voices I can hide John kaku's
tweets and that would hurt him but if
let's for say for instance I just take
somebody else who is in the same field
as you the same market and I uplift that
voice that's gonna pretty much cancel
out what you're doing because more
people going to go to that person we
have that that's coming with pan quake
but you did just mention that the
British government's at war with apple
correct because they want a back door
that's right how do we know for a fact
well we don't know for a fact I mean how
is suie and pan Quake the pan Quake team
going to deal with those same demands
from a trump Administration uh in which
this this operating system is going to
be uh launched under and what are your
thoughts about right now how the Trump
Administration is when it comes to
censorship because a lot of people got
fooled by his executive order that
pretty much said nothing that did
nothing it was just hot air
unfortunately you get people like Mike
Benz and other other people going around
and acting like it's something special
uh give us your overall thoughts on
everything I just kind of unpacked there
as far as what we're GNA do when the
Trump Administration comes knocking
saying we want the back door yeah that's
a great question first let me let me uh
address panqui um this is this is what
so great about being spread out all over
the world um you don't have to deal
directly with the American government or
the British government or any of the
five eyes you know you're based in
you're based in Iceland and you're doing
business all over the place and and you
just keep up the fight number one number
two Trump man this is this is a tough
one Craig this
is listen like you just said not just
said but when you said at the beginning
of the show you come from the left I
come from the left too and I've always
considered myself a leftist leftist even
much more so after I uh left government
and then went to prison for my beliefs
but
um uh it's it's all about the fight I
want I want Donald Trump to do the right
thing I want to believe that these
executive orders are going to lead to
more transparency and freedom of speech
they're not it's all about law fair it's
all about going after your enemies and
can I see a time where Donald Trump or
his administration wants a new back door
to some new uh new platform of course
that's what they always do can you
imagine a white house meeting where cash
Patel uh the the New FBI director or
John rackliffe the new CIA director go
to Trump and say uh Mr President you
know terrorism another
911 uh so we need uh these back doors
yeah you think Trump's going to say oh
no no no I believe in
transparency I believe in freedom of
speech I'm not giving you any back doors
that might save American lives and pre
prevent another 911 of course he's not
going to say that he's gonna give them
what they want just like every single
president before him gave them what they
wanted yeah so it's up to the rest of us
to just
fight yeah well you know he's not going
to come knocking himself he's going to
say send your friend Rudy Giuliani to do
his dirty work that's that's what's
happening don't get me started on Rudy
Giuliani in a in in a very wonderful
world right let's say panqui comes out
and it is widely successful or at least
it it is another outlet that people who
don't want to be under Elon musk's
directive or under meta decide to use
it's it can work panqui all of these can
work with what what Susie calls the
fediverse which is like all of these big
social media apps this mainstream social
media apps that are tied to the US the
Pentagon and all of that how could
something like panqui in your opinion if
we're looking into the future help fight
against genocide for example in Gaza
that we've seen and and the continued
wars in the Middle East how could this
this sort of system eventually help
those causes that is a great great
question and I promise I didn't plant it
it was a naturally occurring question
yeah uh just before I started this this
uh talk with you um I was doing my own
podcast with a Canadian activist by the
name of Eve angler I like you I've known
him for a long time good guy um Eve
wrote an article uh Eve is Canadian he
lives in Montreal and he wrote an
article in which he criticized a
Canadian woman uh she happens to be
Jewish she is a a well-known Zionist he
criticized her um he didn't threaten her
he just criticized her that she doesn't
she doesn't respect human rights of of
Palestinians next thing you know he's
under arrest for hate
speech and all he said was that he
supports Palestinian human rights there
was no hatred there right he ended up
spending five days in jail 40 miles some
prison 40 miles outside of of uh
Montreal and
um he just kept thinking he said that
you know people are going to see how
ridiculous this is I didn't do anything
wrong I have freedom of speech I'm a
Canadian citizen I'm talking about human
rights well they're doubling down he
finally made bail after after five days
in jail and now he's going to go on
trial so then as he gets out of jail
he's getting ready for trial he calls
the arresting officer and he says hey um
can I have um you know whatever whatever
documents police reports you have so I
could give them to my attorney they
charge him with extra crimes they
charged him with four counts of
harassment of a police officer because
he sent a couple of emails and made a
couple of phone calls well you know what
he's suspended from Twitter he's
suspended from Facebook because oh my
God he talks about Gaza you use the GW
and you lose your access to these uh
these these platforms not so with pan
Quake freedom of speech means freedom of
speech where you're free to talk about
anything you want to talk about now
you're not going to post child
pornography or or sell you know fentanyl
or whatever that's not what I'm talking
about I'm talking about freedom of
speech and so uh so I can't help but to
think forgive me if this even sounds
naive but I can't help but to think that
panqui is going to eventually catch on
in a big way because people are
constantly going to be searching for
that transparency that that they can't
find with big Tech this is going to be
your transparency that you've been
looking
for has has pan Quake figured out a way
how they can bring monetization to the
table for their users
yeah it's going to be done on a
subscription basis so you're not going
to be bombarded with ads you know I
still I'm still on Facebook I I went on
Facebook when it first started because I
wanted to see what my kids were doing
and and I wanted to catch up with
friends of mine from high school who are
all old now and don't you know do
anything else um and now you know you
got to go down 25 stories before you
finally get to somebody that you
actually know and follow yeah because
you're just bombarded with dozens dozens
of sites and ads and you might be
interested in you know you know the
history of Cleveland Ohio it's like no
I'm not interested in the history of
Cleveland Ohio and I don't know why you
keep telling me that you think that I
should be so there's not going to be any
of that at pan Quake because it's going
to be subscription based and it's very
modest as well um you're not going to
have to deal with that silliness and
nonsense another thing you know I go on
Twitter I don't even manage my own
Twitter I have a friend who does it for
me um I've got a I've got an online TV
show at unified television so they do it
for me but every once in a while I'll go
on Twitter just to see who's saying what
and I'm bombarded with tweets from Elon
Musk I don't follow Elon Musk yeah I
don't give a [__] what Elon Musk has to
say say about issues of the day or
whatever and every time I try to
unfollow him I'm denied yeah whether you
like it or not you're GNA follow Elon
Musk that's just not the situation at
panqui that's awesome yeah let me let
let me uh pose something to you um and
you know this is a very fundamental
question of freedom of speech right th
this is a very um this this this group
of people that work there are very much
you know anti-establishment types right
but if for example BB Netanyahu wants to
make an account on panqui as far as I
know he will be allowed because freedom
of speech is freedom of speech even for
those you hate correct that's that's
correct yes yeah you know the old saying
um I deplore what you say but I'll die
for your right to say it to say it or
something like that something like um
yeah whatever whatever the the phrase is
I mean if we're serious about this we've
got to be consistent and so yes to
answer your question that would be the
case yeah um yeah I I it's what is it
the uh Nazis in was skoki right like
back in the exact in ski the Nazis
marched in ski 1981 exactly that's where
we need to be we need to get back to
that kind of mentality John I'm kind of
curious um the usaid and Ned right A lot
of people are taking putting a lot of
stock in that I always said that they
are just simply the pr firm for the
regime change industrial complex pretty
much you know the Ned spawned out of the
Reagan Era it was in the middle of Iran
Contra where they knew they were gonna
have a a PR Nightmare and Oliver North
you know I mean pretty much to this day
if you paid attention just slightly paid
attention to what was going on back then
you probably wouldn't fall for this
whole let's go into the Mexico to get
rid of the cartels because you'd
understand that the CIA has a lot to do
with the cartel's power movement of
Banks money product you know right what
are your thoughts on usaid because to me
I say well it's not like the behavior of
Empire is going to change it feels you
know fella has said they're just going
to reappropriate that money into the new
style military that's coming along uh
the QR codes and the satellites and uh
the track and Tra systems what's your
overall thoughts of
usaid uh pretty much something big or
just something to not get too put too
much stock behind oh no no I think this
is a big deal I'm actually glad you
brought it up I've written about this a
couple times in the last few weeks usaid
has well usaid was created in 1961 at
the same time that the Peace Corps and
Vista were created during the Kennedy
administration the idea was terrific
right you create this organization
that's going to go to some of the most
horrible places on Earth and they're
going to do things like dig water wells
and build hospitals or clinics or help
countries uh create water treatment
plants or electrical grids great idea it
never worked that way um even as far
back as the late
60s people who knew called it the cia's
beach head at the state department in
1972 Senator Ted Kennedy wrote a letter
to um the CIA asking if it was true that
the CIA was using usaid for covert
operations much to Kennedy's surprise he
got a a response both from the director
of the CIA and from Henry Kissinger who
was the Secretary of State at the time
the letters were identical they just had
different signatures on them and what
the letter said was yes we use we use
usaid to further CIA covert action
programs now the letter was classified
at the time it's Declassified now but
they said and not just in
1972 we used usaid to funnel money to
laosan rebels in 1969 1970 1971 1972 And
we intend to continue using usaid for
cover action number one there have been
several other operations that have been
Declassified over the years or in one
case accidentally leaked to the media
things like creating um a new um social
media platform called zun zuno during
the George W Bush Administration that
was meant to instigate an Arab Spring
like Uprising in Cuba and Cubans just
went meh not really interested and it
just went away and then somebody leaked
it by accident to the guardian and the
cat was out of the B another one was in
2013 when
um when the Obama Administration tried
to use usaid to overthrow the government
of uh of AO Morales in in Bolivia like
why what do you care if if Eva Morales
is is the president of uh of Bolivia
that you need who you want to
C
that's yeah that's right so you know
this
this is an ongoing thing that has that
has been taking place for decades
decades may I add one thing too Craig if
I have a second sure there there used to
be a Democratic senator from Wisconsin
by the name of William
proxmire um William proxmire won a
special election in 1956 or 57 58 when
uh Joe McCarthy the notorious Joe
McCarthy died and prox Meer prox Meer
was a progressive Democrat who just
hated hated hated
um government
spending and so he created this award
called the Golden Fleece award and he
would give it out once a month at a
press
conference to to whatever governmental
entity was fleing the American
taxpayer the problem was there is no
written down CIA budget that's publicly
available the CIA budget is highly
classified so really nobody knows what
what the budget is what the CIA does is
it takes each line item and it hides it
all over the federal budget it might be
in the Department of Agriculture the
Department of Defense State Department
you know the EPA they're all over the
place so oftentimes prox Meer would see
you know $12 million to study gay
monkeys in Guatemala and he'd say oh
this is an
outrage uh I'm going to give the Golden
Fleece award to whatever office at the
state department is handling this or
usaid as it frequently turned out to be
well there's no there's no $12 million
program to study gay monkeys in
Guatemala that was the cover story that
line item was $12 million from the CIA
budget that had been that had been
embedded there and so the the CIA was
just apoplectic every month when
proxmire would do his uh Golden Fleece
award
well proxmire left the senate in
1998 and nobody like William proxmire
has ever been elected since then um but
the CIA is still doing the same thing it
did when it was trying to dodge his
Golden Fleece award they're still lying
about the budget they're still embedding
covert action uh programs all over
government they're still using usid as
the CIA Beach head at the state
department and they're still using the
American taxpayers money to to try to
overthrow governments that they deem are
not friendly enough to the United
States who's on that list by the way
what what I wonder right I wonder I'd
love to see that list just I just like I
would love to see the Tuesday Morning
kill list which they've never even
admitted
exists well and I was just going to say
it's not like we're really going to get
the truth about Epstein either and it's
not like we're really going to get you
know a lot of these promises for example
JFK uh all of these things are are being
weaponized and there's only a couple
questions I have left to ask you and you
know this is this is all related because
all of this information is being cured
and and spun to us in a certain way on
certain social media platforms whether
it's Facebook you know Twitter X
whatever um and one of the the things I
wanted to ask you was your thoughts on
the Trump zalinski Outburst that
happened because as pasta sort of
mentioned you've seen this push for
Trump as being the hero to come in as
you know getting rid of u USA ID getting
uh the the war in Ukraine to end there
are some you know these are these would
be good things but it seems to me like
the Donald Trump Administration is one
of continuity and and and one that's
going to continue much of the Empire and
just pivot in in in you know to a
different Target so from Russia to the
next targets which we've seen in the
Middle East and and and China as well
and and so it it that's what it seems
like to me so to see this this Outburst
with zalinski right A lot of people are
saying good job Trump you know zalinski
has everything's done with him he's no
longer got the the the show going you
know his his Jig Is up so to speak
but deeper than that do you think that
this signifies something truthful or do
you think
that Donald Trump is just being Donald
Trump which is you know the reality TV
star that he is I think honestly the
answers are yes to all of those so I I'm
a firm believer that the ideological
spectrum is not a straight line from
left to right I think it's a circle and
at some point that Circle meets
uh where progressives and conservatives
can well progressives and and let's say
conservative Libertarians can agree on
specific individual issues um I think
zalinski is done I would not be
surprised if zalinski in the next three
months was a resident of London rather
than Kei I think he's done I think this
war is done I think that uh you know
another thing about Trump Trump does
exactly what he says he's going to do it
can be something terrible like a Muslim
ban for example but I don't know why
everybody's like oh my God I'm so
shocked Trump did exactly what he said
he was gonna do during the campaign I'm
so
shocked um I think that that this war is
coming to a quick end whether uh it
meets Ukrainian goals or
not not is really uh the answer
with that said Trump is wrong about Gaza
Trump is wrong about Syria Trump is
wrong about Iran Trump is wrong about
China there there are a lot of different
places where we can seriously criticize
Donald Trump where he is just an
extension of Empire where where he's not
going to be that that president that
that once in a in a in a century
president who really changes this scope
of American foreign policy or changes
the way the the world uh looks um I'm
genuinely worried about Trump policies
in the Middle East I've spent most of my
adult life in the Middle East I'm an
arabist I speak Arabic I served most of
my career in the Middle East I love
Arabic history and culture and you know
food and poetry and everything and I
genuinely fear for the Palestinian
people under a trump presidency but on
this one issue of the Ukraine war Trump
is right he's right and if we're going
to be we said this offline um before the
show started if we're going to be peace
activists if we're going to be you know
people who go out into the streets and
demand peace then we've got to be
consistent about it and this is one of
those areas where I think we need to
stand up against
War I take it you didn't like the video
with Trump in the golden statue you
didn't we did see that did you see
AI is the craziest dog on thing but I
couldn't tear myself away from it he
shared it he shared and I thought that
like yeah and the funny thing is if you
look at true social he's put up some
polls before about what country is the
greatest threat and who's the biggest
threat to America and a lot of people in
his own base we pointed his out they do
not like the Zionism that's inv they
don't they
and after that video for me first of all
when he said when we'll take over the
Gaza Strip I thought that was really one
of the most disgusting things that
somebody could say that was first of all
it's a war crime it's it is a war crime
and you're EV vacating the terms of the
second phase in which you took credit
for which is you're supposed to pull out
and give the Palestinians back their
territory you're automatically ripping
up the ceasefire in which some people
said he should word the peace award for
that right because we knew it was never
a cease fire because Israel never ceased
to fire but with that heavy dose of
Zionism do you don't you think that a
lot of this time a lot of this stuff
with zalinsky is theater because The Man
Behind zalinski is kisi eigor kisi and
we never see Trump go after him and
that's the guy pulling the strings John
yeah I think maybe Trump thinks he can
do business in a in a post Trump ERA
with
Ki yeah yeah I'm a little worried about
it to tell you the truth yeah there's
pictures of kisi with Ariel Chiron with
Perez I mean he's been in the knesset
and this is the guy calling the shots I
don't know I think it's that's why I get
really frustrated when I see him going
after zilinski knowing zilinski is just
a finger pup EXA he's big your head yeah
yes exactly right so John just last
question bringing it back in because you
all mentioned AI uh you know panqui
isn't going to operate on any Ai and AI
is very popular and all over we have you
know the the gro which is on X you have
the the the Deep seek which is from from
China you have chat GPT you have all of
these AIS coming yes around right so
what what are we looking forward to when
it comes to um panqui and especially now
in an era where you know everything
we're seeing is just so we don't know if
it's real or not and it's getting just
harder to
decipher and that's that's going to be
one of the important pillars I think at
panqui where you're not going to have to
worry about it whether it's AI generated
or not you know and let me tell you
something about AI too in my own
experience um I I I get it that AI is
the future I get that AI uh has
incredible applications that in many
cases can save lives
but
um when it first came out I thought I'm
going to check it out and play around
with a little bit so I said I went to
chat GPT and I said who is John
kiraku and it said John kiraku is a
former CIA officer whistleblower on the
Ci's torture program blah blah blah it
said he earned a bachelor's degree from
the University of Maryland and a
master's degree from the University of
gent in
Belgium and I wrote John kiraku received
bachelor's and master's degrees at
George Washington
University and then AI comes back and
says you are incorrect John kiraku
received his degrees at the University
of Maryland and the University of gent
and I said no you are incorrect and then
it cut me
off that bothered me very much yeah it
cut me off it wouldn't answer any more
of my
questions then um I I I mean Adjunct
professor at at a university in Europe I
teach graduate school classes on um the
history of terrorism at the University
of Salam monka in Spain it's fantastic
place so I I drew up my syllabus for the
year and um and I thought you know what
I'm going to put the syllabus in chat
GPT and see if it can recommend
scholarly articles or books that I may
have missed so I put the whole syllabus
in I asked for it to recommend scholarly
articles you know serious like people's
PhD dis dissertations and stuff like
that so it gave me different citations
for every one of my lectures and every
single one of them was fake every one of
them you click on it and it says 404
error every single one of them it just
made [__] up none of it was real so I I
don't want to live in that world that
that none of that makes any sense to me
it's a human that programs the algorithm
in which the AI is going to run with so
you can cater it to to what you want it
to say and how you want it to act and
they're using AI right now just to flag
us to get us to get to to find out the
the troublemakers right and then bring a
human over to it once the AI Flags it
we're in a very bad sit right now I
agree well uh John uh that's all for for
now I mean you know be doing more of
these talks and and and stuff and you
know there's so much more to to talk
about when it comes to panques so much
more will be coming out in in the next
you know coming weeks and and this year
I mean so much is is left to happen and
with the world kind of going crazy I
think it's almost like I don't want to
say it I don't you know it I don't
believe in coincidences yeah in politics
in life as of late so I I just think the
the the fact that this is coming along
as we are nearing this Tipping Point in
the world is just you know Heaven Sent
or whatever you want to believe in I
agree I agree I'm looking forward to it
very
much skinny kyaku that's John for you
there buddy you look great sound great I
can't wait to see more of this really to
tell you the truth this was needed so
badly I know there's a lot of people who
are kind of hesitant who don't believe
it's going to be Happ they don't want to
hear it anymore but when you guys
eventually punch through and get this
out there I think that all uh all the
past will be forgiven and forgotten and
hopefully we can find a way to move
forward without the uh deep State the
imperialist apparatus whoever's going to
try to shut it down because they do not
want free speech out there ladies and
gentlemen they want controlled speech
and they're going throw everything at
you guys that is it exactly
right uh John where can people find you
by the way if they want to hear more
about you uh everything I do I do on
substack uh so it's just under my name
John kiraku Dos substack
docomo much for tuning in and we will
see you back on next week
Monday yeah bye guys bye
[Music]